[Music]
Every project is a golden opportunity to
shine, impress, and deliver standout
results. Imagine wrapping up a project
that leaves everyone smiling. That's
your moment to shine. But let's be real,
projects can get messy. Deadlines creep
up, follow up emails, uh, slip through
the cracks, and client feedback can pile
up like a neverending to-do list.
Suddenly, staying organized feels
impossible, and old methods uh just
don't cut it anymore. That's where
Floboards steps in. With Flen Boards,
you can manage every detail of your
client projects from kickoff to
completion in one powerful intuitive
platform. It's built to keep you
organized, reduce stress, and make your
workflow seamless. In this video, I'll
guide you through the complete journey
of managing client projects with Flen
Boards, breaking down each step for a
smoother, more confident workflow. So,
let's dive in. So here I'm starting from
the Flynn boards dashboard where
everything I need is right at my
fingertips. As you can see, I have a few
boards uh here that I recently opened.
And this basically makes it super easy
for me to jump back into my work without
searching around from there to there. So
below that I can see my upcoming task
assigned. As you can see it is open by
default. Uh this keeps me you know
updated and ready for what's ahead. So
that way I never actually miss a bit. So
there is also a t for overdue tasks.
Luckily I don't have any right now which
feels great. And next I have a completed
task uh that shown up. It gives me a
sense of you know the achievements and
sometimes keeps me more motivated.
Finally there's a tab for task without
clear deadlines yet. So this could be
things like brainstorming ideas for a
new campaign. This helps me keep track
of everything in one place. Okay. So if
I want I can hide any of these options
from the configured tabs. If I click on
that suppose other options if I unticked
it it will be hide. Okay. You can also
rearrange them if you want from there to
there but I'm not going to do it right
now. And if I take it again it will be
unhide. Okay let's click save now. Nice.
So navigating with ease becomes a
reality uh as my primary controls are
neatly arranged at the top for you know
quick access. So which saving my time.
Let's head to the board section for now.
So this window gives me a clear view of
all the boards I have created. Uh if I
had more than a dozen boards, I can
easily find the one I need by uh
searching uh from it. Suppose I am
looking for client booking management.
If I searched it over there
like client so there are two boards are
appeared one is client booking
management board and one is client
booking management. So if you search in
appropriate way it will be also
appeared. I can even uh filter them by
creation date title or even status. As
you can see there is lot more functions.
Uh if your board is active, you can find
it over from
there. And also there is creation date
and title. You can search or filter by
title. Uh there's also an option to
choose the order like ascending or uh
descending to keep things organized my
way. Plus I have the option to import uh
you know uh boards from CSV
file, other project management platforms
like uh Trello and Asana. I can even
import from the fluent boards like
reusing a setup for a similar project.
So this way you know I don't have to
start from scratch uh which is saving
tons of time and effort. Okay. So for
this project I need to set up a fresh
start since I have a new client with
unique goals. I'll set up my boat to you
know keep me and my team perfectly
aligned with a shared understanding. So
this makes sure uh we are all on the
same page. So let's start with the
title. So I'm going to give a title and
in the next part uh there is a
description uh which should be very
align with your project and work title.
Uh it's like it will be you know gives
you more authenticity um about more
insight about your project that you guys
are going to work and that will also
help you know keeps everyone in the same
target and creating a plan. Okay. So I
have created my descriptions and I'm
just going to add this from there.
Okay, if you want to denote anything you
can do over from there. Okay, just hit
save and my board is already created.
Now that my board is ready, so let's
explore the default setup to keep things
you know moving uh very smoothly. As we
can see Fl has already three stages for
my projects by default. Um as you can
see there is open in progress and
completed uh stages. So there is open
tax basically which is self-explanatory.
It holds all the task that are open like
drafting a project timeline meaning no
one has started working on them yet. Uh
then there's in progress. This actually
includes tasks that have been assigned
and are are being worked on. And lastly
there's the completed tab where all
finished task go. And I can add new
stages if I need to. But I think these
three stages will work perfectly for
this project. So keep adding more for
now. So keeping my project on track
comes uh actually naturally as I create
task with clear to my members. This is
my task title as you can see and just
hit save. Now if you click on that as
you can see there is assignees, dates
and priority. So I'm going uh in the
dates and priority uh after the
assigning uh if I click on the plus
button uh there is a members you know I
just started to create uh asses but I
didn't have any members yet I'll handle
it later. Okay just click it empty and
now I'm going to set the dates for the
task. So the task start date would be 22
and the end 31. I'm going to add the
time frame for
that. Okay, just hit save
now. And here's the priority level since
it is not urgent for me. So, I'm going
to leave it as medium. Okay. And also,
you can uh level up your task from
there. You can just create your level
like
You can choose your colors from there
and just hit save. Okay. You can also
search your levels from there. If I
search search it like by the name it it
will be
appears. Okay. So beneath that I have
the descriptions. So I'll just add the
description so that my asses can know
about uh what expected to be done. So
just add the description for this which
will be very clear for the members.
Okay, just hit save now. So a visually
clear project takes shape with a view
that uh actually suits my style. As you
can see the board is in convent view by
default. You can also choose the list
view. You can see in the
list and there is also calendar. It's
your choice. You can go with the plain
old list or you can pick a calendar view
to see task by date and also perfect for
tracking your deadlines. So I'm just
sticking with the canvan view. So just
like that the filters in dashboard as
you can see uh there's also a filter
here to make things easier. I can filter
task by uh assigne. Um I don't have any
assignees so just hit
unticked. and also seeing only the task
assigned to me such as you know it can
be as writing or report or anything or I
can view task with no assigning if I
click on there you can see that so I can
assign members quickly and keep things
moving. Uh let's get everything
finalized to bring this board to life.
Hang tight for a second. Grab a coffee
if you want and by the time you take
your first tip I'll have my board all
set up completed task uh deadlines and
everything perfectly in place for your
ready to roll. Uh now my board is ready
and the task have been organized
perfectly uh that uh you know setting
the stage for success. So bringing the
right people on board ensures uh task
are handled perfectly and fortunately
fluent boards offers unlimited members.
Uh that means I can add as many team
members I want. uh without any
limitations. So let's go ahead and add
them. They are already user of my
website. So I can add them instantly.
But but what if someone isn't a user of
my website? I can simply type their
email. Okay. And there is a send
invitation button. You just hit the send
invitation and it will be automatically
uh sent. And also, you know, while
inviting someone, I can choose their
access once they're added to the uh
board. Okay? And I can assign them to a
specific task. Just click the task, hit
the plus icon, add them. If I have a lot
of members on my board, I can search uh
for someone by name and add them quickly
without, you know, scrolling through a
long list. But having a client details
at my fingertips becomes simple by, you
know, integrating that info right into
my boat. I can use fluent CRM contacts
to bring that easily as flboards offer
built-in integration with fluenc. So if
I go over here as you can see the CRM
contact I'm just hit over here and just
type the name. As you can
see my CRM contact is over here and just
hit save. After adding them as you can
see there's whole details over here. You
can uh check all the details of your CRM
contact.
Okay. Nice.
So I have some actions right uh here to
make collaboration smooth uh for any
board members with access can assign to
task themselves like if they just hit
join as assigne then they just join as
assigne and
also there is a move moving options if I
click on over here you can as you can
see this is my board and there's also
stage options and from there you can
select any of them there's three options
over here and if I select in progress
the position will be two
okay so if I don't want you know to be
assigned to a task but uh need to keep
an eye on it I can just choose to watch
this uh from this option just hit click
you can watch it okay to make my you
know board visually appealing I need to
update the cover so from this cover
options there is uh multiple colors
available you can choose a solid green
also and also there is options for
uploading image for your custom image
you can upload over here okay I'm just
sticking with this as you can see the
color is shown over here so adding more
details to my task uh you know opens new
possibilities so here's a fresh new
feature which is uh custom fields which
lets me capture specific information uh
directly on my board uh you know this
makes each task more informative and
actionable So uh if you want to add
anything you can do this. So it's not
just about adding fields. It's about you
know making my boards adaptable to any
project needs. Uh so keeping everything
I need in one place. Okay. I'm just
cross it. I don't need anything from
there. And also saving time on future
task you know becomes uh very effortless
by avoiding repetitive uh work. So to
achieve that I can make this task as a
template. So as if I click on make
template as you can see there is a
button create task from template is
shown there. Uh okay. So this will you
know save uh save me a lot of time down
the road. Okay. I can create a task with
just a single click. Just click and it
will be
click. Okay. So here I can set the title
uh choose what information to keep and
also even set the uh stages uh it
belongs to and you know making task
creation a breeze for you. Okay. So I
can also archive the task if I want if I
don't need it anymore. So keep keeping
my board clean and focused.
Okay. I'm just not going to anywhere. So
to ensure my team is performing well I
need to track their progress. So let's
say I want to see the performance of my
uh team members and check uh how they're
doing. So it's always better to keep uh
tabs on everyone to ensure a smooth
workflow, you know, avoiding any delays.
So I can set a predefined time uh for
each task to keep things on schedule. Uh
the question is how can I do that? Okay,
it's very simple. So I just head to the
settings and just go to the features and
modules and here is the time tracking. I
just need to enable it. Just go ahead
and enable. And then go back to the
boards. And here as you can
see, as you can see, I can set an
estimation of how many hours if I click
on you can easily define how many hours
uh that this task will take. Let's say
it will take 10
hours. Okay, just
hit log time.
and you have successfully submitted your
working time. Okay, as you can see, so
if someone's failing behind, I I need to
step in and fix it. So now the question
is what do I do if someone is taking
longer than the estimated time like
spending 5 hours on a 3-hour task to
make things easier and smoother? uh I'll
just add a subtask to this task and uh I
can break it into as many subtask as I
need to split the
workload and after creating those
subtasks uh I can set separate deadlines
for you know uh each and add additional
team members to help out which also
ensures uh a smooth completion of the
task. But what if a subtask is uh you
know taking longer than it should like
uh research dragging on for days. So if
it needs extra attention I can simply
turn that subtask into a main task for
more focus. So this way you know I can
give it the priority it deserves.
Getting a full overview of my project
comes with a detailed report and getting
one has never been this easy. Uh so all
I need to do is head to the reports tab
and click on the time sheet. There I
will see a complete report of what's
happening on my board who's doing what
and how long it's taking them. Okay. So
I can choose a specific board to be more
focused and sort everything by task or
by assigning. It's totally up to you to
decide you know how you want to view it.
Uh keeping in total control. Now I want
to give access to the boards to my
client so they can stay updated but uh I
don't want them to access my back end
and see sensitive info. So question is
how do I handle this? Okay so by taking
my boards to the front end for a secure
view. Uh I just have to toggle this
option from the features and modules
section. Uh then my boards are ready to
be uh on the front end. So let's head
there. I can also invite the client the
same way I invited my team. So just type
in their email. Uh let me type the
email and they will get an invitation
link. Okay. So once they click the link,
they will need to add some info before
getting access. So after they submit
those uh they will be redirected to the
board. Now they can view all the tasks
to stay in the loop. Uh add comments to
give feedback or use the attachment
feature to add resources. So I can
change their access anytime like uh
switching them to edit mode or even
remove them from the board easily if
needed keeping everything you know under
my control. Okay. So let's polish off my
board with some handy features to uh
streamline my workflow even more. Uh for
example uh the board activity feature uh
lets board members see all the activity
in a single place. Uh making it easy to
keep uh keep tabs on everything without
searching. But checking the board every
time for updates can be a hassle. So uh
the question is how you can tackle this.
Fun boards offers a notification
features. I can set which notifications
I want and those notifications will be
sent to me via email keeping me in the
loop. I can also change the background
uh to make my board more visually
appealing. um you know adding a solid
color like uh you can take blue um a
gradient for a modern look or even an
image like a team photo uh as my
background. Remember the levels I set
for my task like I can uh customize all
the levels easily from here. So then
there's the archived item. So if I
archive any task or stages uh they can
be found here and I can restore them or
delete them permanently if I don't need
them. So I can even archive the entire
board from here if the project is done
uh keeping my workspace clean. So if I
have more than one client's information,
I can see all those contacts right here.
And finally, if I have a similar
project, I can simply duplicate this
board. And this will save me a lot of
time uh and the hassle of creating a
board from a sketch and making it making
my next project a base. All right, I
have uh wrapped it up. My client
projects are set to shine brighter than
ever. I have overcome the chaos of
deadlines uh task and feedback with
ease. So, Flenboards made it simple uh
guiding me from start to finish in one
smooth platform. So, let's keep working
my projects with Fls.